[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我告诉你这个故事是因为我想
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I told you that story because I want to
向你介绍Kerckhoff一家。
introduce you the Kerckhoffs.
Kerckhoff是个很棒的人
Kerckhoffs was an amazing guy.
防弹装置爆炸后，他的情况变得很糟糕，
After the bulletproof thing exploded, things went really bad for him,
他的健康受到了影响，它只是，它变坏了。
his health suffered and it just, it went bad.
但就在他和他们扯上关系之前，
But just before he got involved with them,
他写了第一本关于现代密码学的书。
he wrote the first book about modern cryptography.
在Kerckhoff之前，密码学被理解为秘密代码的科学，
Prior to Kerckhoffs, cryptography was understood as the science of secret codes,
一般写在纸上的代码。
generally codes written on pieces of paper.
Kerckhoff在电子通信的基础上重新发明了密码学
Kerckhoffs reinvented cryptography based on electronic communication
因为他们现在通过电报和房产发送信息
because they were now sending messages through the telegraph and the properties
电报的性质与纸张的性质完全不同。
of the telegraph are radically different from the properties of paper.
他解决了这个问题
And he worked this stuff out and
提出了一套原则，今天人们仍然认为这些原则是正确的。
came up with a set of principles which are still understood to be true today.
他是这些令人惊叹的思想家中的一员，他非常聪明，所以
He was one of these amazing thinkers who's just so smart and so
远远领先于他的时代。
far ahead of his time.
所以他写的其中一个东西叫做Kerckhoff原则
So one of the things he wrote is called The Kerckhoffs Principle and
他说系统的设计不应该要求保密和
he said the design of a system should not require secrecy and
系统的妥协不应给通信人员带来不便。
compromise of the system should not inconvenience the correspondents.
让我来演示一下他在这里说的是什么。
So let me demonstrate what he's talking about here.
所以我们有两个通讯员爱丽丝和鲍勃，他们需要沟通和
So we have two correspondents Alice and Bob and they need to communicate and
他们不想在这样做的时候被观察到。
they don't want to be observed while they're doing that.
所以他们有一个密码系统。
So they have a cryptographic system.
在这个加密系统中，Alice获取她的消息，她的明文和
In this cryptographic system, Alice takes her message, her plain text and
把它放在加密机里。
puts it in an encryption machine.
她还将密钥放入加密机，然后输出密文。
She also puts a key into the encryption machine and out comes a cipher-text.
然后她将密文传输给Bob和
She then transmits the cipher-text to Bob and
这是完全有可能的电线被观察到，任何人都可以看到它。
it's entirely possible that that wire is being observed and anybody can see it.
Bob收到密文，他把它放进他的解密机，可能是
Bob receives the cipher-text, he puts it in his decryption machine which may be
与爱丽丝的加密机相同并且也放入相同的密钥，
identical to Alice's encryption machine and also puts in the same key,
他们在之前的一次会面中交换了这一点，这使他能够获得平原
which they exchanged in a prior meeting, and that allows him to obtain the plain
文本，这基本上就是所有密码系统的工作方式。
text and this is basically how all cryptographic systems work.
Kerckhoff说的那件事
The thing that Kerckhoffs said which was so
令人惊讶的是，加密机中没有秘密。
amazing was that there are no secrets in the encryption machine.
系统中唯一的秘密是密钥和
The only secret in the system is the key and
我仍然看到今天的人们，学者们说，我们应该尽量保持
I still see people today, academics who are saying, we should try to keep as
为了挫败攻击者，我们的大部分系统都是私有的。
much of our system private as we can in order to frustrate the attackers.
Kerckhoff说不，保护好钥匙，这就是你要做的。
Kerckhoffs said no, just protect the keys, that's all you have to do.
他是对的，因为在默默无闻中没有安全。
And he was right and he was right because there is no security in obscurity.
事实证明，你拥有的秘密越多，就越难保守
And it turns out the more secrets you have, the harder they are to keep and
只是保证钥匙的安全真的很难。
just keeping the keys safe is really hard.
所以你应该把所有的注意力都集中在这上面。
So you should focus all of your attention on that.
有些人接受柯克霍夫原则
There are some people who take The Kerckhoffs Principle so
至于说我们应该发布除了密钥之外的关于我们系统的所有内容，
far as to say we should publish everything about our system except our keys,
这种态度的好处是你从来不会困惑
the good thing about that attitude is you're never confused about
你系统中的重要秘密是什么？
what are the important secrets in your system.
所以密码术不是安全的，而是
So cryptography is not security but
密码学家思考问题的方式
the way that cryptographers think about problems
是一种非常有用的思维方式，我们也应该这样思考。
Is a really useful way of thinking and we should think like that too.
所以我会试着教你像密码学家一样思考。
So I'm gonna try to teach you to think like a cryptographer.
我将通过教授加密系统来做到这一点
I'm gonna do that by teaching about a cryptographic system
叫做一次性垫子。
called the One Time Pad.
这是唯一保证真实的加密系统
This is the only cryptographic system which is guaranteed to be truly
牢不可破。
unbreakable.
在所有其他加密系统中，如果您有足够的时间和
In all other cryptographic systems, if you have enough time and
足够的计算机能力，最终你可以蛮力，尝试每一个键和
enough computer power, eventually you can brute force, try every key and
最终你会打破这个系统。
eventually you'll break the system.
不可能与一个系统，保证牢不可破，这是非常好的。
Not possible with a system, guaranteed unbreakable which is pretty nice.
有传言说白宫和
There are rumours that the hotline between the White House and
克里姆林宫是用一次性密码板加密的。
the Kremlin is encrypted with the One Time Pad.
这就是它的工作原理。
So this is how it works.
我们有很多必须遵守的规则。
We have a number of rules that we have to follow.
第一个是密钥必须始终保持秘密。
The first one is that the key must always remain secret.
每一个密码系统都是如此。
This is true of every cryptographic system.
第二，密钥必须至少与纯文本一样长。
Number two, the key must be at least as long as the plain text.
这真的很不寻常。
Now this is really unusual.
在大多数密码系统中，密钥是某种固定大小的，并且
In most cryptographic systems, the key is some fixed size and
消息往往比密钥长得多。
the messages tend to be much longer than the key.
这一条说密钥必须至少和消息一样长。
This one says the key has to be at least as long as the message.
然后通过异或运算得到密文
Then the cypher text is obtained by Exclusive-ORing
纯文本和密钥。
the plain text and the key.
这就是算法。
That is the algorithm.
这就是系统的实现，所以它非常简单。
That is the implementation of the system, so it's really, really simple.
所以让我向你们演示一下。
So let me demonstrate it to you.
这是我的纯文本。
This my plain text.
这是JSON徽标。
This is the JSON logo.
我用它是因为我可以。
I'm using it because I can.
通常你认为一个纯文本就是一个文本，但这是一个数组和
Usually you think of a plain text as being a text, but this is an array of ones and
零，对吧？
zeros, right?
所以我们可以加密它。
So we can encrypt that.
这是我的钥匙。
This is my key.
密钥与消息的大小相同。
The key is the same size as the message.
我要对它们进行异或运算，如果我做对了，
I'm going to Exclusive-OR them together and if I do this correctly,
你不应该看到任何迹象，任何幽灵，任何原始信息的窃窃私语。
you should not see any sign, any ghost, any whisper of the original message.
如果信息被完全遮蔽，隐藏在噪音中，
If a message is completely obscured, hidden in the noise,
那么我已经正确加密了。
then I have encrypted it correctly.
下一个规则是密钥必须是完全随机的，或者
The next rule says that the key must be perfectly random or
密码随机。
cryptographically random.
获得这种随机性是很难的。
Getting that kind of randomness is hard.
现在我费了很大的劲才把它放进钥匙里。
Now I went to a lot of trouble to get that into my key.
所以让我告诉你如果你不这么做会发生什么。
So let me show you what happens if you don't.
所以这是一把钥匙，它看起来就像我先给你看的那把钥匙，
So this is a key, it looks just like the key I showed you first,
除了我在Photoshop里用噪音滤镜做的这个，好吧
except I made this one in Photoshop with a noise filter, okay and
Photoshop的噪波过滤器不保证是加密随机的。
Photoshop's noise filters are not guaranteed to be cryptographically random.
所以如果我用这个弱键对纯文本进行异或，你可以看到它，对吗？
So if I Exclusive-OR my plain text with this weak key, you can see it, right?
漏水了。
It's leaking through.
这就是地窖分析师在破解密码时所寻找的东西。
This is what crypt analysts are looking for when they're breaking codes.
他们在寻找任何一种模式，
They're looking for any kind of pattern,
任何通过噪音泄漏的信号。
any kind of signal that's leaking through the noise.
你正在用你的大脑破解一个牢不可破的代码，
You are breaking an unbreakable code with your brain,
你甚至都不努力工作。
and you're not even working hard at it.
你能做到这一点的原因是你的视觉系统
And the reason you're able to do that is your visual system
在分离信号和噪声方面非常有效，并且
is extremely effective at separating signal from noise, and
这就是密码分析员在试图破解代码时所做的事情。
that's what crypt analysts do when they're trying to break a code.
下一个规则非常重要，它是系统的名称。
The next rule is so important, it is the name of the system.
一个密钥绝不能使用多次。
A key must never be used more than once.
所以系统如何使用的比喻是我将打印
So the metaphor for how the system is used is I will print
两本相同的随机数书。
two identical books of random numbers.
我会留着一个，我会给你另一个。
I will keep one, I will give you the other one.
当我想给你加密信息的时候，我会拿第一张纸，
When I want to encrypt a message to you, I will take the first sheet,
我会把它撕掉，我会用它加密，然后我会毁掉它。
I will tear it out, I will encrypt with it, I will then destroy it.
当您收到消息时，您将采取相应的
When you receive the message, you will take the corresponding
从你的书里拿出一张纸，你会用它解密，然后你会毁掉它。
sheet out of your book, you will decrypt with it, and you will destroy it.
你再也不会用它了。
You will never use it again.
这就是为什么它被称为一次性垫子。
That's why it's called the One Time Pad.
那么，如果我们违反了这条规则，会发生什么呢？
So what happens if we violate that rule?
这是我的照片
So this is a picture of me.
这是在伊斯坦布尔拍摄的。
This was taken in Istanbul.
我用它是因为我可以。
I'm using it because I can.
你会意识到这是我给你看的第一把钥匙。
This, you'll recognise is the first key that I showed you.
这是第一把好钥匙
This is the first good key and
我要用这个加密我的图片，再一次，它是完全隐藏的。
I'm going to encrypt my picture with that and again, it's completely hidden.
我现在要对这个进行异或运算
I'm now going to Exclusive-OR this one with
我得到的第一个密文。
the first cipher text that I obtained.
所发生的是因为它们各自与一个密钥进行异或运算，
And what happens is because they each are Exclusive-ORed with a key,
密钥将取消，剩下的两条消息是异或的
the key will cancel out and I'm left with the two messages Exclusive-ORed
彼此之间没有安全保障。
with each other and there is no security in that.
所以密码术不是安全的，
So cryptography is not security,
但是密码学可以教给我们关于安全的东西。
but cryptography can teach us stuff about security.
我发现的是
It's something I've found is that
我们经常错误地思考如何使用密码学。
often we think incorrectly about how to use cryptography.
如果我看到某人的系统
If I'm looking at someone's system and
它们中有明显的安全漏洞，我指出它们
there are obvious security vulnerabilities in them and I point them out to
架构师，架构师的第一反应是，我们需要加密一些东西。
the architect, the architect's first response is, we need to encrypt something.
结果证明是行不通的。
That turns out not to work.
但是像密码学家一样思考，这确实有效
But thinking like cryptographers, that does work and
他们用来思考的工具之一
one of the tools that they use for thinking
他们有一组角色用来对他们的系统进行推理。
is they have a cast of characters who they use for reasoning about their systems.
我们已经见过爱丽丝和鲍勃了。
We've already met Alice and Bob.
它们是密码学节目中的标准人物，
They are standard characters in the cryptographic show,
但是还有很多其他的角色。
but there are lots of other characters.
例如，有夏娃。
For example, there is Eve.
伊芙是个窃听者。
Eve is an eavesdropper.
例如，EVE可能有数据包嗅探器，EVE可能是NSA。
Eve might have a packet sniffer and Eve might be NSA for example.
伊芙在看爱丽丝和爱丽丝之间的一切
Eve is looking at everything that's going between Alice and
Bob和Eve希望积累足够的东西
Bob, and Eve is hoping to accumulate enough stuff that
最终她会有足够的信息来破坏他们的系统或者至少
eventually she'll have enough information to break their system or at least
能够观察他们的通信模式并进行流量分析。
be able to observe the pattern of their communication and do a traffic analysis.
然后是马洛里
Then there is Mallory.
马洛里可以做男人在中间，男人在中间攻击。
Mallory can do man in the middle of it, man in the middle attacks.
Mallory可能正在操作公共热点，因此Bob连接
Mallory might be operating a public hot spot, and so Bob connects
马洛里的网络以为他会和爱丽丝连接，但是
to Mallory's network thinking that he's gonna connect to Alice, but
他实际上和Mallory有联系。
he's actually connected to Mallory.
Mallory连接到Alice，Bob尝试登录。
Mallory connects to Alice and Bob tries to log in.
Mallory问Bob，你的密码是什么，Mallory连接到Alice。
Mallory asks Bob, what's your password, Mallory connects to Alice.
爱丽丝说你的密码是什么，马洛里把鲍勃的密码给了爱丽丝。
Alice says what's your password, Mallory gives Bob's password to Alice.
现在他告诉爱丽丝，请把我的钱转过来。
Now he tells Alice, please transfer my funds.
马洛里对爱丽丝说，请更改我的密码。
Mallory says to Alice, please change my password.
Mallory对Bob说，很抱歉我们现在下来了，请稍后再来。
Mallory says to Bob, I'm sorry we're down right now, please come back later.
这是我们应该担心的吗？
Is that something we should be worried about?
是的，我们应该担心这个，是的。
Yeah, we should be worried about that, yeah.
最后，在我自己的实践中，我有一个角色，我称之为撒旦。
And then finally in my own practice, I have a character I call Satan.
撒旦完全是恶毒的。
Satan is totally malicious.
他非常强大，他非常聪明，他非常坚定。
He was very, very powerful, he is very, very smart, he's very, very determined.
他有资金，他有工具，他想伤害我们和我们的客户。
And he's financed, he's got the tools and he wants to hurt us and our customers.
有些人对他采取的方法就是说好，
The approach that some people take to him is to say well,
我们不会让他和我们联系。
we won't let him connect to us.
你知道如果你是撒旦，你就不能连接。
You know if you're Satan, you can't connect.
这就是所谓的黑名单，那是行不通的。
That's called a blacklist and that doesn't work.
在互联网上，很容易就能创造出新的身份
On the Internet, it is so easy to create new identities that
你不能这么做，因为他会变成另一个人。
you can't do that because he'll just be somebody else.
所以另一种方法是我们将允许每个人都与我们联系
So the other approach is we will allow everybody to connect to us who
不是撒旦。
is not Satan.
这是一个白名单，在这种情况下也不起作用。
That's a white list and that doesn't work either in this case.
唯一起作用的就是认识到撒旦
The only thing that works is recognising that Satan
会和我们联系，他会对我们做什么
is going to connect to us and he is going to do to us and
我们的客户，无论我们允许他对我们和我们的客户做什么。
our customers whatever we allow him to do to us and our customers.
所以我们有责任把每件事都做好，这样我们的能力
And so we have a responsibility to do everything right so that the capabilities
我们给予撒旦的东西是如此有限，如此软弱，以至于他不能伤害我们。
that we give to Satan are so limited and so weak that he cannot cause us harm.
这是唯一有效的方法。
That is the only thing that works.
其他的都不管用。
Nothing else works.
正因为如此，我们做出的每一个决定都必须考虑到安全因素。
So because of that, security must be factored into every decision we make.
我们所做的一切都有安全隐患
Everything we do has security implications and
对撒旦来说，要么能让事情变得更好，要么让事情变得更糟。
can either make things better or worse for Satan.
不安全感的一个重要来源是我们会回去
One big source of insecurity is the idea that we'll go back and
以后再保证安全。
make it secure later.
很常见的是，正在建造某件东西的工程师们会苦思冥想
It's very common that engineers who are building something will think the hard
一部分是让系统启动，或者让盒子说话，或者
part is going to be to get the systems to boot, or the boxes to talk, or
屏幕上的像素。
the pixels on the screen.
一旦我们这样做了，2，0将返回并添加安全性。
Once we've done that, 2,0 will go back and add security.
结果发现这不管用。
Turns out that doesn't work.
安全是一件很难改造的事情。
Security is a really hard thing to retrofit.
你需要在一开始就把事情做好，而且一直都是这样。
You need to get the stuff right at the beginning and all along all the time.
你不能增加安全性，就像你不能增加可靠性一样。
You can't add security just as you can't add reliability.
这些都是必须删除的东西。
These are things that have to be removed.
你必须消除不安全感。
That you have to remove insecurity.
你必须消除不可靠。
You have to remove unreliability.
您不能添加它们。
You can't add them.
活到这一点并不能保证未来的生存。
Having survived to this point does not guarantee future survival.
所有在网上做生意的人都受到了攻击
Everybody who does business on the web has been under attacked
自从万维网诞生以来，他们还没有摧毁我们，但是
since the beginning of the web and they have not destroyed us yet, but
这并不能保证他们不会，所以你必须时刻保持警惕。
that does not guarantee that they won't and so you have to always remain vigilant.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：不可能是不可能的，所以
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: The impossible is not possible, so
不要指望不可能的手段来保护你。
don't expect impossible means to protect you.
如果一个措施无效，它就是无效的，并且
If a measure is not effective, it is ineffective, and
我们不应该在它上面浪费任何时间或注意力。
we should not be wasting any time or attention on it.
不要试图禁止你不能阻止的事情。
Don't attempt to prohibit what you can't prevent.
而你不能阻止的就是你允许的。
And what you don't prevent, you allow.
错误的安全性比没有安全性更糟糕，因为如果您
False security is worse than no security because if you
知道你不安全，你会谨慎，如果你认为你安全
know you're not secure, you'll be cautious and if you think you're secure and
你不是，你会鲁莽的。
you're not, you will be reckless.